A Guide to the James H. Latimer Papers, 1864-2000
Library of Virginia
- Subject Files
  - Election Results
    - Democratic Primary (Governor, Lt. Governor, and Attorney General), 1925-1957 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - General Election (Governor, Lt. Governor, and Attorney General), 1929-1961 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Virginia State Senate and House of Delegates (also Supervisors, Soil Conservation Districts), 1959-1967 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Virginia State Senate and House of Delegates (also Supervisors, Soil Conservation Districts), 1947-1958 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Republican Primary (Governor, Lt. Governor, and Attorney General), 1949 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Virginia (Governor) (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Virginia (President, U. S. Senate and House of Representatives), 1924-1962 (Box 12, Folder 16-19)
    - Virginia (President, U. S. Senate and House of Representatives), 1964-1978 (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
    - Virginia (President), 1872-1980 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Elections
    - Presidential and Congressional, 1932 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Presidential and Senatorial, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Presidential (clippings and Sabato analysis), 1992 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Presidential, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Presidential and Congressional, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - State and Local, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - U. S. Senate (Paul Trible vs. Dick Davis), 1982 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - U. S. Senate (John Warner vs. Edythe Harrison), 1984 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - U. S. Senate (Chuck Robb vs. Oliver North vs. J. Marshall Coleman) (I-II), 1994 (Box 13, Folder 12-13)
    - U. S. Senate Republican Primary (John Warner vs. Jim Miller), 1996 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - U. S. Senate (John Warner vs. Mark Warner), 1996 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Virginia Democratic Gubernatorial Primary (Lt. Governor's Race), 1945 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Virginia Democratic Gubernatorial Primary (Remmie L. Arnold), 1949 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Virginia Democratic Gubernatorial Primary (Horace Edwards), 1949 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Virginia Democratic Gubernatorial Primary, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Virginia General Assembly (I-II), 1995 (Box 13, Folder 20-21)
    - Virginia Gubernatorial (William Mahone), 1889 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Virginia Gubernatorial, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Virginia Gubernatorial (I-II), 1981 (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
    - Virginia Gubernatorial, 1985
      - I-II (Box 14, Folder 3-4)
      - Transcript of debate between Baliles and Durrette, 17 Aug. 1985 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Gubernatorial, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Gubernatorial (J. Marshall Coleman), 1989 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Gubernatorial, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Virginia Gubernatorial ("A Century of Politicking for Governor in Virginia"), 1997 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Falwell v. Flynt (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Ferebee, J. Smith (article in The Commonwealth, Oct. 1961) (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Freeman, Douglas Southall (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Genealogy
    - Howe Family (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - "The Latimers Since the War" (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - "Mama Mac: The Early Years" (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Ginter Park (Richmond, Va.) (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Glasgow, Ellen
    - Ellen Glasgow Newsletter, 1979-1983 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Henry W. Anderson and the 1921 Gubernatorial Election (I-II) (Box 15, Folder 3-4)
  - Godwin, Mills E., Jr.
    - Godwin, Mills E., Jr. (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Genealogy (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Memoirs (1990) (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Seibel cartoons, 1965-1968 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - GOP Loyalty Pledge (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Gridiron Club, 1971, 1981, 1983, 1987, 1991, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 10-15)
  - Gubernatorial Addresses
    - Gerald L. Baliles, 11 Jan. 1986 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Colgate W. Darden, 12 Jan. 1944 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Linwood Holton, 9 Jan. 1974 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - George Campbell Peery, 8 Jan. 1936, 12 Jan. 1938 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - John Garland Pollard, 15 Jan. 1930 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - James H. Price, 14 Jan. 1942 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Charles S. Robb, 18 Jan. 1982 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - E. Lee Trinkle, 1 Feb. 1922, 3 Mar. 1922, 9 Jan. 1924, 13 Jan. 1926 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - William M. Tuck, 14 Jan. 1948, 11 Jan. 1950 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Guerry, Alexander - In Memorium (President, University of Chattanooga (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Guest, Raymond R. "Andy" - campaign for Republican nomination as Governor, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Hall, Grover C., Jr. - resignation as editor of the Richmond News Leader (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Hall, John Hopkins, Jr. - resignation as Labor Commissioner, 1949 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Hardy, Porter, Jr. (obituary) (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Harrison, Albertis S.
    - Funeral article and Godwin remarks; retirement from Virginia Supreme Court (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - "Selected Speeches of Albertis S. Harrison, Jr., 1962-1966" - Table of contents (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Virginia Project Foundation (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Health (I-II) (Box 16, Folder 15-16)
  - Hermitage Country Club - Newsletters, May 1982, May 1983, Apr. 1996 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Hill, Oliver - Election to Richmond City Council, 1948 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Hill, Oliver and Samuel Tucker, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Holton, Linwood (clippings, correspondence, campaign material) (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Hotels - Hotel Richmond and Murphy's (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Howe, Murry M. - Resolution of respect, 10 Apr. 1996 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Howell, Henry
    - Abstract of Remarks to State AFL-CIO Annual Convention, 10 Aug. 1979 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Flier - Henry Howell Reunion, 25 Aug. 1979 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Campaign Material (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - 1969 Gubernatorial Election (clippings) (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Hudgins, Edward Wren (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Jefferson - Lakeside Country Club (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Jefferson - Jackson Day Dinner, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Jefferson, Thomas (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Jones, Overton (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Journalism (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Kelley, George (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Latimer family; McCrary family (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Latimer, Anna Mary McCrary (wife) - Memorial Service Program, 25 June 1993 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Latimer, Hugh, Bishop (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Latimer, Hugh Darington (father) - National Geographic Society and stock certificate (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Latimer, James D. (son)
    - National Aquatic School, 14 - 24 Aug. 1962 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Term Paper, Valuation Report on a home in Gainesville, Florida (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Latimer, James H.
    - Biographical information (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Latimer, James H. (grandfather)
    - Sympathy cards, obituaries, clippings (I-II) (Box 17, Folder 13-14)
    - United Confederate Veterans; photograph, 11 May 1933 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Latimer, Ollie Mai Howe (mother) - Account Book, Circle # 4 Auxiliary, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Lee, Robert E. - Portrait (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Lindbergh, Charles A. - Visit to Virginia, Oct. 1927 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Lowance, Carter O. (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - MAC 491 (VCU School of Mass Communications), 1995 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Mackenzie, Ross (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - MacNelly, Jeff (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Maps
    - Richmond and Washington, D. C. (includes Amtrak timetable) (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Tidewater and Environs (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Virginia Revolutionary War Map, 1774-1783 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Topographical - Shenandoah National Park, Central Section (1980) (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Marshall (George C. Marshall) Day, VMI, 15 May 1951 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Marshall-Wythe School of Law - Bicentennial, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Massive Resistance (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Mays, David - Secret Diaries
    - Article, Richmond Times Dispatch,22 Sept. 1996 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence and Memos, Jan. - Oct. 1996 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Excerpts, 1914, 1917, 1926, 1955-1959, 1970-1971 (Box 18, Folder 5-7)
    - Notes and background material (Box 18, Folder 8-9)
    - Rough Drafts (Box 18, Folder 10-11)
  - McDowell, Charles (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Media General, Inc. (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Miller, Andrew Pickens (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 19, Folder 2-4)
  - Miscellaneous - press passes, business cards, book titles, receipts, membership cards (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Montague, Andrew Jackson (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Moore, E. Blackburn - In Memoriam, 22 July 1980 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Mullet - rules, score sheets, minutes, etc. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Newsletters - Scott Meredith Literary Agency, Inc.; The 333 News (Richmond Newspapers Inc.); RAG Times (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Obenshain, Richard (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Obituaries (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Oral History Forum of the Virginia Library Association (correspondence and notes for talk given at VLA Annual Conference), 9 Nov. 1979 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Political Conventions
    - Democratic National, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Democratic National, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Democratic National, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Democratic and Republican National, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Democratic National - 1968 (delegates' list); 1972 (seating plan); 1976 (press kit folder); 1980 (ticket); 1984 (delegate selection plan); 1988 (delegates' list), 1968-1988 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Republican National, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Republican National, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Republican National (I-IV), 1976 (Box 20, Folder 1-4)
    - Republican National ( Russell Record, 21 and 23 Aug. 1976) (V), 1976 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Republican National, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Republican National (List of Virginia's Delegates), 1988 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Republican, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Virginia Republican, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Virginia State Democratic, 1960 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Virginia State Democratic, 1968 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Virginia State Democratic, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Virginia State Democratic, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Popham, John (managing editor, Chattanooga Times) (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Postcards - Nashville (Tenn.), Davy Crockett (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Powell, Lewis F., Jr. (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Presidential Inauguration (press kit), 1965 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Presidential Nominating Process (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Presidential Press Conferences (I-III) (Box 21, Folder 2-4)
  - Press Releases (including LBJ speech with Byrd, Sr. reactions), 1955-1986 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Prince Edward County - Segregation Suit (clippings) (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Programs - Musical Performance and plays (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Prohibition
    - Alan Burton Clarke (I) (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - "Seventeen Years in the Desert" by Alan Burton Clarke (pp. 1-173 - Introduction, Chapters 1-4, Conclusion) (II-III) (Box 21, Folder 9-10)
  - Quayle, Dan - Washington Post articles, 5 - 12 Jan. 1992 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Rawlings, George C., Jr. - Campaign brochure, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Reporter's Note Books (I-II) (Box 21, Folder 13-14)
  - Reports
    - "Toward A New Dominion: Choices for Virginians (Report of the Governor's Commission on Virginia's Future)," Dec. 1984 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - "Metropolitan Virginia: A Program for Action," 15 Nov. 1967 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - "The Virginia Public School System: Report of the Virginia Education Commission," 1944 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - "Report of The Commission to Study the State Government of Virginia," 1 Sept. 1961 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - "The Reorganization of the Agencies of State Government," 13 Nov. 1949 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Republican Party Platform, 1952 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Reynolds Family (Reynolds Metal Co.) (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Reynolds, J. Sargeant (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Richmond City Council - history (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Richmond Colts - program, 1951 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Richmond - Hospital Needs - Richmond Times-Dispatch,Jan. 1952 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Richmond Newspapers, Inc. - proposed history (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Richmond Times-Dispatch and Richmond News Leader merger (clippings), 1991-1992 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Richmond Times-Dispatch - Task Force on Design and Appearance Report; Content Committee Report, 7 Aug. 1987 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Richmond - "Trafficway Plan for Richmond," City Planning Commission, Apr. 1951 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Robb, Chuck
    - Robb, Chuck (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Presidential speculation (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - 1984 Presidential Election (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Robb - Wilder, 1985-1986, 1991 (Box 22, Folder 14-15)
  - Robertson, A. Willis - Tributes to in the Congressional Record,27 May 1965 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Rolfe, Shelley (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Saint Thomas' Episcopal Church - Directory, Aug. 1990 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Saunier, Paul - columns, Dec. 1982 - Jan. 1983 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Sawgrass Village (Ponte Vedra Beach, Fla.) (I) (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Sawgrass Village (Ponte Vedra Beach, Fla.) (II) (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Schoolwork
    - May 1927, Dec. 1928 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - University of Chattanooga
      - 1932 (Box 23, Folder 3-4)
      - Assignment and notebook, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Grades, book reports, news report on the 3rd annual Dixie press convention (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Principles of Economics (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Psychology, English, Philosophy, 1932 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Merry X-Mas to James Howe from Sara and Mary, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Clippings and miscellaneous material re: the Arts, Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, Etc. (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous articles (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - SDX - Freedom of Information - Secrecy in Government, 1967-1968 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Segregation - Schools (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Seibel, Fred O. - Copies of editorial cartoons, 1956, 1960-1968 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Seminar for Southern Journalists, 31 Mar. - 4 Apr. 1968 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Smith, Howard W.
    - Book review ("Keeper of the Rules" by Bruce J. Dierenfield) (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Campaign brochure, 1946 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Smith, William "Extra Billy" (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Southampton County, Photographs of (re: Nat Turner's Rebellion), Apr. 1967 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Speeches (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Spong, William B. (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Stephens, A. E. S. "Gi" and Mosby Perrow - Resolutions passed by General Assembly upon their death, 1974 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Stoddart, George (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Taft Seminar for Teachers, 1984-1992 (Box 24, Folder 14-21)
  - Thompson, Lorin A. (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Time, Inc. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Travel
    - 1990-1991 (Box 25, Folder 2-6)
    - Graves Mountain Lodge, Virginia Wineries, Skyland, Shenandoah National Park (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - New York hotels (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Truman, Harry S - Conflicts with Harry F. Byrd, Sr. (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Tuck, William M.
    - Tuck, William M. (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Birthday tribute, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - United States Constitution
    - 200th Anniversary (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Bicentennial (Virginius Dabney interview, materials for teachers, notes), 1987 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - "Constitution of the United States," Encyclopedia Americana (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - The Jefferson Meeting on the Constitution, Feb. 1984 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - The Jefferson Meeting (includes material from the Illinois Jefferson Meeting, 1984), 1985 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - United States Supreme Court - Court cases involving Virginia (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - University Echo (University of Chattanooga student newspaper), 1 Apr. 1932, 4 Nov. 1932, 16 Dec. 1932, 26 May 1933, 1 Apr. 1982 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - University of Richmond - 125th Anniversary, 29 Oct. 1955 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - University of Virginia
    - Alderman Library (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - James H. Latimer Endowed Fellowship Fund, 1987 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Virginia Communications Hall of Fame (nominations), 1985-1995 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Virginia Communications Hall of Fame, 1987 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Virginia Constitutional Convention, 1829-1830 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Virginia Court Day Forums - Grant application, 1983 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Virginia Democratic Party (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Virginia's Executive Mansion (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Virginia Financial Crisis, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Virginia General Assembly (Young Turks), 1954 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Virginia General Assembly, 1962, 1980, 1983, 1986, 1990, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Historical Society (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Virginia's Inaugural Ceremonies - History and programs, 1954, 1962, 1974, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Military Institute (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Virginia's Political Bosses (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Virginia Political Party Development (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Virginia Politics
    - Comparison between Fairfax and Halifax Counties (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Election results, biographical information on governors, political parties (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Maps of House of Delegates districts, State Senatorial districts, and Congressional districts (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 27, Folder 14-15)
  - Virginia Presidential Politics - Miller Center of Public Affairs, University of Virginia - "Four Virginia Governors," 31 Oct. 1996 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Virginia's Primary (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Virginia Rebuttal Dinner (Sorenson Institute), 12 May 1997 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Virginia Senators (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Virginia State Capitol (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Warner, John - Birthday salute, 26 Feb. 1983 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - White Burkett Miller Center of Public Affairs (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Whitehead, Robert
    - "The Political Career of Robert Whitehead" by William B. Obrochta (M. A. Thesis, Univ. of Richmond, 1985), pp. 1-220 (Box 28, Folder 5-7)
    - Remarks regarding State Interposition, 1 Feb. 1956 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Wilder, L. Douglas
    - Wilder, L. Douglas (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Lt. Governor's Campaign, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Wilkinson, J. Harvie, III - Campaign pamphlet, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Williams, Ernest Howard (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Woodrow Wilson Foundation (addresses), 1978-1987 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Young Republicans - Eastern Young Republican College Conference (Charlottesville), 16-17 Mar. 1951 (Box 28, Folder 14)
- Publications
  - Arlington County, Virginia (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - "Beesley's Illustrated Guide to St. Michael's Church, Charleston, So. Ca.," by Charles Norbury Beesley (1898) (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Brunswick County, Virginia (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Civil War Publications (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - The Commonwealth, Nov. 1954, June 1955, Jan. 1956, Aug. 1956 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - "The Financial Affairs of McCarthy" (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - "The History of the Republican Party, 1854-1956" (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - "The Honorable George Wythe" - An Address by Oscar L. Shewmake, Esquire (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - King William County (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Leesburg, Virginia (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - "The Lewis and Clark Expedition" (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - "The Lost Colony, 1587-1947 - 360th Anniversary Celebration" (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - The M-G News - Dec. 1976, Aug. 1978, May 1981, Feb. 1982 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - The M-G News - Feb. 1987, Apr. 1987, Oct./Nov. 1997 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - "The Mystic Symbol," by John D. Freeman, 1932 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - "The N. C. & St. L. RY. News Item," May 1924 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - The New Yorker - "Georgia I and Georgia II", 6 and 13 Feb. 1978 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - "Richmond's Architecture," by Robert P. Winthrop - reprinted from Richmond Times-Dispatch,9 Aug. - 11 Oct. 1981 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - "Sockdolager! A Tale of Davy Crockett" (distributed by the Virginia Commission of Constitutional Government) (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - T-D Topics, 1979-1989 (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Time, 21 Aug. 1964 (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - Time - "Special 1776 Issue," 4 July 1976 (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Time - "Special Bicentennial Issue," 26 Sept. 1789 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Today in Virginia, 13 Nov. 1968, 25 Nov. 1968, 5 May 1969 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - United Confederate Veterans Programs, 1932, 1934 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - University of Virginia Newsletters, 1948-1996 (Box 30, Folder 4-6)
  - Virginia Business, Apr. 1989 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Cavalcade, Winter 1995, Winter 1996, Spring 1981, Summer 1995 Spring 1955, Autumn, 1976, Autumn 1954 (Box 30, Folder 8-11)
  - Virginia Magazine of History and Biography (Vol. 87, No. 1), Jan. 1979 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Virginia and the Virginia Record, Jan. 1954, Aug. 1954 (Box 30, Folder 13-14)
  - Virginia Record - "The History of the Virginia General Assembly," Jan. 1964 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - The Washington Post Magazine, 17 July 1988, 7 Aug. 1988, 28 Jan. 1996 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Westmoreland County, Virginia (includes pamphlet on the Leedstown Resolutions) (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Newspapers (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - "A Century of History From the Front Pages of the Richmond Times-Dispatch & the Richmond News Leader," 1978, 1983, 1986 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Richmond News Leader,"It seems like only Yesterday," Special Commemorative Magazine, 30 May 1992 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - "Welcome To Richmond Newspapers" (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Country Gentleman, Aug. 1937 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 14 May 1870 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - The Ladies' Home Journal, Sept. 1915 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Life - 6 Dec. 1963; John F. Kennedy Memorial Edition; 23 June 1972 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - "The Little Small Red Hen" (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Look, 3 Dec. 1963 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - The New York Times Book Review, 15 Mar. 1970 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - The Washington Post Magazine, 14 Jan. 1979 (Box 31, Folder 12)
- Writings
  - Articles, 1937-1938, 1940-1941, 1947, 1950, 1957, 1960-1969 1970-1975 1976-1979 1980-1984, 1990, 1994 (Box 31, Folder 13-17)
  - Rough Drafts, 1970, 1974-1979, 1980-1982, 1989, 1990, 1993, 1995 (Box 31, Folder 18-19)
  - Scrapbook (articles re. Henrico - Richmond annexation and miscellaneous) (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Sunday Columns (rough drafts, clippings, and columns), 1972-1981, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 21-22)
  - Sunday Article - "The Message of Mount Rushmore" (includes article, notes, and background material), 10 Oct. 1976 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - "Virginia Politics, 1950-1960" (116 pp., written in 1961) (Box 32, Folder 2)
- Photographs
  - Accepting George Mason Award, 5 June 1979 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - At Work (I-VII) (Box 32, Folder 4-10)
  - 1977 Democratic Gubernatorial Primary - Henry Howell and Andrew Pickens Miller (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Almond, J. Lindsay, Jr. - color negatives (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Berry Hill Plantation (Halifax County, Va.) (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Bratton, Madison (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Byrd Family (William Byrd II, William Byrd III, Harry F. Byrd, Sr. inauguration, Harry F. Byrd, Jr. wedding) (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - "Conferences of Chief Justices" - Visit to Virginia, Sept. 1950 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Courthouses - Brunswick, Greensville, Hanover, King William, Sussex, and Westmoreland Counties (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Dalton, John (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Dalton, Ted (autographed photograph) (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Danville Public Library (Last White House of the Confederacy) (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Ellyson, J. Taylor (photograph of portrait) (Box 32, Folder 21)
  - Godwin, Mills E., Jr. (autographed photograph) (Folder 32, Folder 22)
  - Godwin, Mills, John Dalton, and Linwood Holton, 1978 (Box 32, Folder 23)
  - Holton, Linwood (Box 32, Folder 24)
  - Howell, Henry (photograph of portrait) (Box 32, Folder 25)